Help on module cv2.fisheye in cv2:

NAME
    cv2.fisheye

FUNCTIONS
    calibrate(...)
        calibrate(objectPoints, imagePoints, image_size, K, D[, rvecs[, tvecs[, flags[, criteria]]]]) -> retval, K, D, rvecs, tvecs
        .   @brief Performs camera calibaration
        .   
        .   @param objectPoints vector of vectors of calibration pattern points in the calibration pattern
        .   coordinate space.
        .   @param imagePoints vector of vectors of the projections of calibration pattern points.
        .   imagePoints.size() and objectPoints.size() and imagePoints[i].size() must be equal to
        .   objectPoints[i].size() for each i.
        .   @param image_size Size of the image used only to initialize the intrinsic camera matrix.
        .   @param K Output 3x3 floating-point camera matrix
        .   \f$A = \vecthreethree{f_x}{0}{c_x}{0}{f_y}{c_y}{0}{0}{1}\f$ . If
        .   fisheye::CALIB_USE_INTRINSIC_GUESS/ is specified, some or all of fx, fy, cx, cy must be
        .   initialized before calling the function.
        .   @param D Output vector of distortion coefficients \f$(k_1, k_2, k_3, k_4)\f$.
        .   @param rvecs Output vector of rotation vectors (see Rodrigues ) estimated for each pattern view.
        .   That is, each k-th rotation vector together with the corresponding k-th translation vector (see
        .   the next output parameter description) brings the calibration pattern from the model coordinate
        .   space (in which object points are specified) to the world coordinate space, that is, a real
        .   position of the calibration pattern in the k-th pattern view (k=0.. *M* -1).
        .   @param tvecs Output vector of translation vectors estimated for each pattern view.
        .   @param flags Different flags that may be zero or a combination of the following values:
        .   -   **fisheye::CALIB_USE_INTRINSIC_GUESS** cameraMatrix contains valid initial values of
        .   fx, fy, cx, cy that are optimized further. Otherwise, (cx, cy) is initially set to the image
        .   center ( imageSize is used), and focal distances are computed in a least-squares fashion.
        .   -   **fisheye::CALIB_RECOMPUTE_EXTRINSIC** Extrinsic will be recomputed after each iteration
        .   of intrinsic optimization.
        .   -   **fisheye::CALIB_CHECK_COND** The functions will check validity of condition number.
        .   -   **fisheye::CALIB_FIX_SKEW** Skew coefficient (alpha) is set to zero and stay zero.
        .   -   **fisheye::CALIB_FIX_K1..fisheye::CALIB_FIX_K4** Selected distortion coefficients
        .   are set to zeros and stay zero.
        .   -   **fisheye::CALIB_FIX_PRINCIPAL_POINT** The principal point is not changed during the global
        .   optimization. It stays at the center or at a different location specified when CALIB_USE_INTRINSIC_GUESS is set too.
        .   @param criteria Termination criteria for the iterative optimization algorithm.
    
    distortPoints(...)
        distortPoints(undistorted, K, D[, distorted[, alpha]]) -> distorted
        .   @brief Distorts 2D points using fisheye model.
        .   
        .   @param undistorted Array of object points, 1xN/Nx1 2-channel (or vector\<Point2f\> ), where N is
        .   the number of points in the view.
        .   @param K Camera matrix \f$K = \vecthreethree{f_x}{0}{c_x}{0}{f_y}{c_y}{0}{0}{_1}\f$.
        .   @param D Input vector of distortion coefficients \f$(k_1, k_2, k_3, k_4)\f$.
        .   @param alpha The skew coefficient.
        .   @param distorted Output array of image points, 1xN/Nx1 2-channel, or vector\<Point2f\> .
        .   
        .   Note that the function assumes the camera matrix of the undistorted points to be indentity.
        .   This means if you want to transform back points undistorted with undistortPoints() you have to
        .   multiply them with \f$P^{-1}\f$.
    
    estimateNewCameraMatrixForUndistortRectify(...)
        estimateNewCameraMatrixForUndistortRectify(K, D, image_size, R[, P[, balance[, new_size[, fov_scale]]]]) -> P
        .   @brief Estimates new camera matrix for undistortion or rectification.
        .   
        .   @param K Camera matrix \f$K = \vecthreethree{f_x}{0}{c_x}{0}{f_y}{c_y}{0}{0}{_1}\f$.
        .   @param image_size
        .   @param D Input vector of distortion coefficients \f$(k_1, k_2, k_3, k_4)\f$.
        .   @param R Rectification transformation in the object space: 3x3 1-channel, or vector: 3x1/1x3
        .   1-channel or 1x1 3-channel
        .   @param P New camera matrix (3x3) or new projection matrix (3x4)
        .   @param balance Sets the new focal length in range between the min focal length and the max focal
        .   length. Balance is in range of [0, 1].
        .   @param new_size
        .   @param fov_scale Divisor for new focal length.
    
    initUndistortRectifyMap(...)
        initUndistortRectifyMap(K, D, R, P, size, m1type[, map1[, map2]]) -> map1, map2
        .   @brief Computes undistortion and rectification maps for image transform by cv::remap(). If D is empty zero
        .   distortion is used, if R or P is empty identity matrixes are used.
        .   
        .   @param K Camera matrix \f$K = \vecthreethree{f_x}{0}{c_x}{0}{f_y}{c_y}{0}{0}{_1}\f$.
        .   @param D Input vector of distortion coefficients \f$(k_1, k_2, k_3, k_4)\f$.
        .   @param R Rectification transformation in the object space: 3x3 1-channel, or vector: 3x1/1x3
        .   1-channel or 1x1 3-channel
        .   @param P New camera matrix (3x3) or new projection matrix (3x4)
        .   @param size Undistorted image size.
        .   @param m1type Type of the first output map that can be CV_32FC1 or CV_16SC2 . See convertMaps()
        .   for details.
        .   @param map1 The first output map.
        .   @param map2 The second output map.
    
    projectPoints(...)
        projectPoints(objectPoints, rvec, tvec, K, D[, imagePoints[, alpha[, jacobian]]]) -> imagePoints, jacobian
        .   @overload
    
    stereoCalibrate(...)
        stereoCalibrate(objectPoints, imagePoints1, imagePoints2, K1, D1, K2, D2, imageSize[, R[, T[, flags[, criteria]]]]) -> retval, K1, D1, K2, D2, R, T
        .   @brief Performs stereo calibration
        .   
        .   @param objectPoints Vector of vectors of the calibration pattern points.
        .   @param imagePoints1 Vector of vectors of the projections of the calibration pattern points,
        .   observed by the first camera.
        .   @param imagePoints2 Vector of vectors of the projections of the calibration pattern points,
        .   observed by the second camera.
        .   @param K1 Input/output first camera matrix:
        .   \f$\vecthreethree{f_x^{(j)}}{0}{c_x^{(j)}}{0}{f_y^{(j)}}{c_y^{(j)}}{0}{0}{1}\f$ , \f$j = 0,\, 1\f$ . If
        .   any of fisheye::CALIB_USE_INTRINSIC_GUESS , fisheye::CALIB_FIX_INTRINSIC are specified,
        .   some or all of the matrix components must be initialized.
        .   @param D1 Input/output vector of distortion coefficients \f$(k_1, k_2, k_3, k_4)\f$ of 4 elements.
        .   @param K2 Input/output second camera matrix. The parameter is similar to K1 .
        .   @param D2 Input/output lens distortion coefficients for the second camera. The parameter is
        .   similar to D1 .
        .   @param imageSize Size of the image used only to initialize intrinsic camera matrix.
        .   @param R Output rotation matrix between the 1st and the 2nd camera coordinate systems.
        .   @param T Output translation vector between the coordinate systems of the cameras.
        .   @param flags Different flags that may be zero or a combination of the following values:
        .   -   **fisheye::CALIB_FIX_INTRINSIC** Fix K1, K2? and D1, D2? so that only R, T matrices
        .   are estimated.
        .   -   **fisheye::CALIB_USE_INTRINSIC_GUESS** K1, K2 contains valid initial values of
        .   fx, fy, cx, cy that are optimized further. Otherwise, (cx, cy) is initially set to the image
        .   center (imageSize is used), and focal distances are computed in a least-squares fashion.
        .   -   **fisheye::CALIB_RECOMPUTE_EXTRINSIC** Extrinsic will be recomputed after each iteration
        .   of intrinsic optimization.
        .   -   **fisheye::CALIB_CHECK_COND** The functions will check validity of condition number.
        .   -   **fisheye::CALIB_FIX_SKEW** Skew coefficient (alpha) is set to zero and stay zero.
        .   -   **fisheye::CALIB_FIX_K1..4** Selected distortion coefficients are set to zeros and stay
        .   zero.
        .   @param criteria Termination criteria for the iterative optimization algorithm.
    
    stereoRectify(...)
        stereoRectify(K1, D1, K2, D2, imageSize, R, tvec, flags[, R1[, R2[, P1[, P2[, Q[, newImageSize[, balance[, fov_scale]]]]]]]]) -> R1, R2, P1, P2, Q
        .   @brief Stereo rectification for fisheye camera model
        .   
        .   @param K1 First camera matrix.
        .   @param D1 First camera distortion parameters.
        .   @param K2 Second camera matrix.
        .   @param D2 Second camera distortion parameters.
        .   @param imageSize Size of the image used for stereo calibration.
        .   @param R Rotation matrix between the coordinate systems of the first and the second
        .   cameras.
        .   @param tvec Translation vector between coordinate systems of the cameras.
        .   @param R1 Output 3x3 rectification transform (rotation matrix) for the first camera.
        .   @param R2 Output 3x3 rectification transform (rotation matrix) for the second camera.
        .   @param P1 Output 3x4 projection matrix in the new (rectified) coordinate systems for the first
        .   camera.
        .   @param P2 Output 3x4 projection matrix in the new (rectified) coordinate systems for the second
        .   camera.
        .   @param Q Output \f$4 \times 4\f$ disparity-to-depth mapping matrix (see reprojectImageTo3D ).
        .   @param flags Operation flags that may be zero or CALIB_ZERO_DISPARITY . If the flag is set,
        .   the function makes the principal points of each camera have the same pixel coordinates in the
        .   rectified views. And if the flag is not set, the function may still shift the images in the
        .   horizontal or vertical direction (depending on the orientation of epipolar lines) to maximize the
        .   useful image area.
        .   @param newImageSize New image resolution after rectification. The same size should be passed to
        .   initUndistortRectifyMap (see the stereo_calib.cpp sample in OpenCV samples directory). When (0,0)
        .   is passed (default), it is set to the original imageSize . Setting it to larger value can help you
        .   preserve details in the original image, especially when there is a big radial distortion.
        .   @param balance Sets the new focal length in range between the min focal length and the max focal
        .   length. Balance is in range of [0, 1].
        .   @param fov_scale Divisor for new focal length.
    
    undistortImage(...)
        undistortImage(distorted, K, D[, undistorted[, Knew[, new_size]]]) -> undistorted
        .   @brief Transforms an image to compensate for fisheye lens distortion.
        .   
        .   @param distorted image with fisheye lens distortion.
        .   @param undistorted Output image with compensated fisheye lens distortion.
        .   @param K Camera matrix \f$K = \vecthreethree{f_x}{0}{c_x}{0}{f_y}{c_y}{0}{0}{_1}\f$.
        .   @param D Input vector of distortion coefficients \f$(k_1, k_2, k_3, k_4)\f$.
        .   @param Knew Camera matrix of the distorted image. By default, it is the identity matrix but you
        .   may additionally scale and shift the result by using a different matrix.
        .   @param new_size
        .   
        .   The function transforms an image to compensate radial and tangential lens distortion.
        .   
        .   The function is simply a combination of fisheye::initUndistortRectifyMap (with unity R ) and remap
        .   (with bilinear interpolation). See the former function for details of the transformation being
        .   performed.
        .   
        .   See below the results of undistortImage.
        .   -   a\) result of undistort of perspective camera model (all possible coefficients (k_1, k_2, k_3,
        .   k_4, k_5, k_6) of distortion were optimized under calibration)
        .   -   b\) result of fisheye::undistortImage of fisheye camera model (all possible coefficients (k_1, k_2,
        .   k_3, k_4) of fisheye distortion were optimized under calibration)
        .   -   c\) original image was captured with fisheye lens
        .   
        .   Pictures a) and b) almost the same. But if we consider points of image located far from the center
        .   of image, we can notice that on image a) these points are distorted.
        .   
        .   ![image](pics/fisheye_undistorted.jpg)
    
    undistortPoints(...)
        undistortPoints(distorted, K, D[, undistorted[, R[, P]]]) -> undistorted
        .   @brief Undistorts 2D points using fisheye model
        .   
        .   @param distorted Array of object points, 1xN/Nx1 2-channel (or vector\<Point2f\> ), where N is the
        .   number of points in the view.
        .   @param K Camera matrix \f$K = \vecthreethree{f_x}{0}{c_x}{0}{f_y}{c_y}{0}{0}{_1}\f$.
        .   @param D Input vector of distortion coefficients \f$(k_1, k_2, k_3, k_4)\f$.
        .   @param R Rectification transformation in the object space: 3x3 1-channel, or vector: 3x1/1x3
        .   1-channel or 1x1 3-channel
        .   @param P New camera matrix (3x3) or new projection matrix (3x4)
        .   @param undistorted Output array of image points, 1xN/Nx1 2-channel, or vector\<Point2f\> .

DATA
    CALIB_CHECK_COND = 4
    CALIB_FIX_INTRINSIC = 256
    CALIB_FIX_K1 = 16
    CALIB_FIX_K2 = 32
    CALIB_FIX_K3 = 64
    CALIB_FIX_K4 = 128
    CALIB_FIX_PRINCIPAL_POINT = 512
    CALIB_FIX_SKEW = 8
    CALIB_RECOMPUTE_EXTRINSIC = 2
    CALIB_USE_INTRINSIC_GUESS = 1

FILE
    (built-in)


